# Akshay Shewani

**Quant Analytics & BI** 

Data-Driven Decision Maker & Analytics Leader with a Passion for Innovation. Experienced in providing insights to businesses, with a prime focus in driving sales and marketing efforts using Advanced Analytic Techniques in the Institutional, Wealth Management & Marketing domain.

akshayshewani@gmail.com

+91 99303 35524



Mumbai, INDIA

inkedin.com/in/akshay-shewani-93a5662b

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **AVP Quant Analytics & BI**

JP Morgan Chase

08/2021 - 2024

Key Responsibilities/Tasks

- Created customer segmentation model to recommend sales touch points with clients based of client engagement
- POC For Conversational BI using LLMs
- Created a scalable rule based recommendations engine for Sales advisory teams based off user engagements
- Customer Lifetime value prediction engine to rationalize sales and marketing efforts
- Recommendation engine responsible for driving context of ~ \$1 Billion in sales
- Personalized recommendation engine model based off feedback from sales users
- Created a customer segmentation model to identify Business at risk
- Created engine to analyze holding performance and recommend take over opportunities
- Created Product of Interest model based off Web engagement

## Senior Manager Big Data & Advanced Analytics Morgan Stanley Advantage Services

09/2016 - 08/2021

Kev Responsibilities

Mumbai

- Lead the Advanced Analytics team tasked with generating recommendations for the CRM system users using rule and statistical models
- Creating Data Pipelines for integration with Various Data Sources as batch
- Managed & lead the effort for Integration Stock Plan data (20 Mill participants ) & holdings) into existing CRM system
- Lead the design effort for integration & orchestration of E-Trade data
- Responsible for preparing the roadmap for the team and the project
- Integration of E\*Trade data resulting in 5 Mil leads having over \$360 Bill AUM
- Analyze Adobe Clickstream data for user journeys to provide context to engagement
- Salesforce Data Integration for Firm Clients and FAs across applications using ETL
- Prediction of client attrition based on user behavior patterns
- Analysis and prediction of unusual sales patterns using product sales information

## **Data Analytics**

## Credit Suisse (On Demand Agility)

11/2015 - 10/2016 Proiects/Tasks

Pune

- Analyzing requirements based of FED regulations with respect to CCAR Reporting for 14A Trading MTM
- Liaise with stakeholders to identify factors impacting VaR Reporting
- Analyze existing reporting systems to identify the structure of expected data
- Incorporate Data Ingestion pipelines and implement data cleansing strategies
- Identify Trade and Scenario attributes in the existing framework that may be used
- Working with front office to procure additional Scenarios and Sensitivity data

#### **Data Analyst**

#### Smartstream Technologies

08/2012 - 11/2015

Mumbai

- Analysis/Mapping for exchange derivatives data to SmartStream Data model
- Defining cross referencing rules to create unified feeds from multiple data sources
- Defining data cleansing rules to ensure only quality data enters the system
- Coordinating with the Exchange for additional information on data feeds

## **SKILLS**

Python PySpark Machine Learning Deep Learning **SQL** Redshift **Project Management** 

## **CERTIFICATES**

AWS Cloud Practitioner (04/2022)

General Assembly Data Science Essentials (02/2020 - 05/2020)

CFA Level 2

EPAT (Executive program in Algorithmic Trading) (12/2016 - 05/2017)

CDAC (ACTS PUNE) (02/2012 - 08/2012)

## **EDUCATION**

PG Data Science (Indian School of Business) (2023 - 2024)

Indian School of Business

Bachelor of Computer Application (2011) Naapur University

#### **LANGUAGES**

#### **Enalish**

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

#### Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

#### SUPPORTED CAUSES

Animal welfare Women Empowerment Children's Education

## INTERESTS

Boxing

Football

Music